activelylearn.com 2019-01-01

# Actively Learn - Privacy Policy

Actively Learn Inc. “Actively Learn“ developed this Privacy Policy in order for you to understand how we collect, store, use, communicate and disclose your information.

###  **INTRODUCTION**

Actively Learn is committed to protecting the privacy of the students and teachers who use our products and services. We want you to know how we use your information, and how students, their parents, teachers, and administrators have control over that information.

  * We collect the bare minimum of personally identifiable information necessary (first name, last name, username, and class) for students to establish an account on Actively Learn and be identified by their teacher and associated with the work students do in our application. 
  * Students’ and teachers’ personally identifiable information is stored securely on our servers and protected with numerous technological and procedural safeguards. 
  * We do not sell or lease students’ or teachers’ personal information to third parties for advertising, marketing, or other purposes.
  * We are compliant with FERPA and COPPA.

By using Actively Learn, you agree to this Privacy Policy. If you don’t agree with this policy or have any questions about it, you can contact us anytime at privacy@activelylearn.com.

‍

###  **COLLECTION AND USE OF INFORMATION**

####  **Personally Identifiable Information**

Personally identifiable information ( **PII** ) is data that personally identifies you, such as your name, mailing address, email address or credit card information. We may collect personal information from you for a variety of reasons such as processing your order for the purchase of a product or service, registering your product, enabling the use of certain features of a product, supporting a solution, downloading a software update, communication for marketing purposes from Actively Learn, creating an Actively Learn ID, or managing a job application. The PII we collect is different for teachers and staff, students under 18, and children under 13. For example, we collect first and last name, email, and school name and address for each teacher or staff member. Billing address and payment details are collected and passed to our payment processor but are not stored by Actively Learn. For students under 18, we collect first and last name and school name for each student, and the email address if school policy or technical infrastructure requires students to create accounts on Actively Learn using their email address (e.g., Google Classroom schools).

We may use PII for internal purposes such as data analysis and research to improve our products, services and content. We may also use PII to send you important notices regarding product purchases or changes to our terms and conditions or policies, and to occasionally contact teachers and staff to answer questions, resolve issues they or their students may encounter while using our product, and to inform them of new features on our platform. If you provide personal information of a third party, we will assume that you have the third party’s permission to provide such information. Student PII is used only to provide the Actively Learn service to the student and authenticate the student when logging in. It is **not** used for advertising of any kind nor any other non-educational purpose. 

Here are examples of how we collect user information:

  *  **Account information:**  When an educator or student creates an account on Actively Learn, we collect their name, email address, school, and, depending on the method of signup, a password for accessing their Actively Learn account. They also have the option of uploading a profile picture. Students cannot create an account by themselves; their teacher must first create a class in Actively Learn and invite students to join it.
  *  **Credit card and billing info:** When teachers purchase content or upgrade to a premium plan, we collect credit card and billing information and pass it securely along to our payment processor, Stripe. We do not store credit card and billing information on our servers.
  *  **Communications:** Actively Learn collects communications that teachers and administrators send us directly via e-mail and through our in-app support system.
  *  **Classroom content:** We collect instructional content created by teachers on our platform when they build assignments including questions, notes, links, and media, student work including discussion and question answers, and teacher assessment of student work including grades and feedback.
  *  **Analytics and log data:** When you use Actively Learn, we collect additional identifying information including your IP address as well as metadata about your browser version and operating system. We also collect analytics on platform and feature usage, including metrics such as reading time. 

We use this information only to provide the Actively Learn service to you. For example, we use this information to:

  * Allow you to access your Actively Learn account and to create and teach lessons in Actively Learn.
  * Notify you about activity in your classes (if you’ve indicated in your account settings that you’d like notifications).
  * Provide you with customer support.
  * Research, understand, and analyze usage trends to improve Actively Learn and develop new features.

As described in this policy, Actively Learn uses administrative, technological and physical safeguards to protect personal information against loss or theft, as well as unauthorized access, disclosure, copying, use or modification.

### PARENTAL CONSENT

Teachers and schools are required to get parental consent before setting up student  accounts, or asking students to set up their own account, for students who are not legally old enough to give their consent for these purposes. The age varies by country, and in the U.S. it is 13. There are several ways to get parental consent. For teachers in the United States, the most common method is to act as the parent’s agent and provide consent on their behalf, which an educator or institution may do as long as they use Actively Learn solely in an educational context as provided by the FTC. [Learn More](https://www.ftc.gov/tips-advice/business-center/guidance/complying-coppa-frequently-asked-questions#Schools).

###  **FERPA and COPPA COMPLIANCE**

For U.S. users, Actively Learn’s data protection and privacy policies and practices comply with FERPA (Family Education Rights & Privacy Act), COPPA (Children's Online Privacy Protection Act), and other applicable federal and state education privacy laws. 

We only collect personal information from children in the United States who are under 13 if the child’s parent or legal guardian has provided us with the necessary consent, or if the child’s educational institution has contractually agreed to obtain parental consent for the child to use Actively Learn’s services and to disclose information to us for educational purposes. Parents and legal guardians of these users have the right to review or have deleted the child’s personal information and refuse to permit its further collection or use by emailing [privacy@activelylearn.com](mailto:privacy@activelylearn.com).

If you have reason to believe that a child under 13 years old has provided Actively Learn with personal information, and that child’s parents or school have not provided Acitvely Learn with the adequate consent, please contact us at privacy@activelylearn.com.

For further information about FERPA and COPPA compliance, or to access, modify, or remove any personal data, please contact us at [privacy@activelylearn.com](mailto:privacy@activelylearn.com). To the extent that a provision in this policy conflicts with a provision in FERPA, COPPA, or another state or federal education privacy law, Actively Learn will abide by the more restrictive provision.

###  **HOW  WE KEEP YOU PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION SAFE**

The security of PII is a top priority for Actively Learn. Actively Learn has protections in place to ensure our user's data is secure, and we routinely review and update these protections. We have administrative, technical, and physical safeguards in place designed to protect against unauthorized use and disclosure of or access to personal information. Specifically:

  * Amazon's AWS cloud infrastructure has been designed and is managed in [compliance with regulations, standards, and best-practices](https://aws.amazon.com/compliance/), including HIPPA, SOC 1/SSAE 16/ISAE 3402 (formerly SAS70), SOC 2, SOC 3, PCI DSS Level 1, ISO 27001, FedRAMP, DIACAP and FISMA, ITAR, FIPS 140-2, CSA, and MPAA.
  * The Amazon AWS region where Actively Learn stores it's servers and database is [FedRAMP compliant](https://aws.amazon.com/compliance/fedramp/).
  * Actively Learn encrypts all data at rest and in transit between the Actively Learn web application and Actively Learn's servers using TLS/SSL.
  * All user information is stored in our secure database.
  * All server and database configuration and management is strictly controlled and executed solely by Actively Learn's engineering team in Seattle, WA.
  * Actively Learn's engineering team use 2-factor authentication to access and manage ALL parts of our service and infrastructure to prevent unauthorized access even in the unlikely event one of our engineer’s passwords is compromised.
  * All Actively Learn team members use 2-factor authentication whenever possible to access other 3rd party services we use in the course of business for the same reason.

###  **NON-PERSONALLY IDENTIFYING INFORMATION**

We also collect non-personally identifying information (non-PII), which is data in a form that does not allow for direct or indirect identification with any specific individual Such non-PII may be collected through use of Actively Learn software and through cookies, web logs, web beacons and other similar applications. Any questions, notes, comments, feedback or other material created by you in Actively Learn software (but which does not identify you personally) also fall within this definition of non-PII.

We use this non-PII to better understand customer behavior and improve the performance, features, sophistication and effectiveness of our products, software, services and websites.

###  **DISCUSSIONS, NOTES, FEEDBACK, and RESPONSES**

If you participate in discussions, create shared notes, answer questions, provide feedback, or otherwise share your ideas, comments, or opinions on or in an Actively Learn product, software, or website, please note that the information you provide in these ways will be made available to others and can be read, collected or used by other participants. Any notes, responses, or feedback posted are the participants’ opinions/comments and should not be construed as an opinion or comment of Actively Learn. We are not responsible for any information, including Personal Information, that participants choose to post or share when using Actively Learn products, software, services or websites.

###  **DISCLOSURE  TO THIRD PARTIES**

We will not sell or lease any teacher's or student's personal information with third parties for their advertising, marketing, or other purposes. We will not sell, lease, or share PII of students under 18 or children under 13 to third parties for any purpose, except (1) To comply with laws or a legal process such as responding to a subpoena or court order; (2) To exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims. We may share personal information with a teacher’s or student’s current or prior educational institution for authorized educational/school purposes.

###  **THIRD  PARTY SITES AND SERVICES**

Actively Learn’s products, software, services or websites may reference or contain links to third-party websites, products or services. In addition, our products, software, services or websites may use products or services from third parties. [Here](https://www.activelylearn.com/subprocessors) is the list of third party subprocessors we use to assist us in offering Actively Learn. We do not share student data with third parties for any purpose other than the correct functioning of the Actively Learn service and only if they also adhere to the same terms and principles outlined here. When these third party subprocessors transfer personal data of EU residents, these services are processors and are bound to also comply with GDPR to protect your data privacy and security.

If you have further questions about a specific third party, we encourage you to learn about the privacy policies of such third parties directly.

If you choose to include embedded video in your Actively Learn lessons from providers such as Youtube, those providers may display ads during the course of video playback. Please note that Actively Learn does not have control over whether ads appear in embedded videos. The ads are placed by the video provider (e.g. Youtube), and ad revenue generated goes to the video’s provider and creator, not Actively Learn. Also, the independent reading catalog available in the premium plans contains links to third party website content that may contain advertising.

###  **ACCESS  AND ACCURACY OF PERSONAL INFORMATION**

We will make good faith efforts to honor reasonable requests to access or correct personal information if it is inaccurate or delete the data if Actively Learn is not required to retain it by law or for legitimate business purposes.

###  **RETENTION  OF PERSONAL INFORMATION**

Actively Learn will keep your information for the period needed to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy unless a longer period is required by law.

###  **DELETING  YOUR ACCOUNT AND DATA**

Any user can request deletion of their account and data by sending an email to privacy@activelylearn.com. Parents can request deletion of their child’s data by sending a request to privacy@activelylearn.com. The data will be deleted within 48 hours of confirming the request.

###  **QUESTIONS**

If you have any privacy-related questions or comments related to this Privacy Policy, please send an email to us at privacy@activelylearn.com.

###  **UPDATES  TO THIS POLICY**

We may update this Privacy Policy from time to time. If we change our Privacy Policy, we will post the updated version here with the updated revision date. We will not make material changes to our Privacy Policy (i.e. changes that weaken existing privacy protections) without providing prominent notice to account holders and giving account holders a choice before using data in any manner inconsistent with the terms account providers were originally provided.

This policy was last updated on May 25, 2018.

‍
